Mobile: +9647827017193
Email: alhassanjabbar@yahoo.com

BRIEF SUMMARY

Profile: Male, 28, Married

Nationality: Iraq

• Current position: procurement and inventory analyst

• Company: Shell (SIPD)

Residence: Basra- Mishraq district

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Career Objective:

Determined and capable Logistic Professional with over7+ years of experience in, procurement, inventory, Warehousing and Material managements in Multinational Oil and Gas Company. **Seeking challenging role and opportunity to explore my strengths and areas of developments and keen to learn and contribute in a diverse and professional organization**. Highly adaptable and quick learner and can work and deliver under challenging work conditions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Company: EXXONMOBILE (westqurna1 oil field).

Period: Jun 2018-present.

Position: Iraq warehouses manager.

In my current role I am responsible of all warehouses and materials activities and my key Responsibilities as below.

- I am managing all warehouses operation for asset, project and drilling and wells work warehouses added to that three big pipes yards.
- Responsible to manage stock of about 39000 unique materials, a stock value of about 100 million USD.
- Responsible of managing preservation contract to preserve all the materials we have to be ready for field operations at any time.
- Managing the stock check for all the stock we have and make sure we have the same physically and in Maximo system.
- Supervisor for 50 persons with below positions.
 - 1. Materials lead (5 expats and 6 iraqi locals).
 - 2. Senior inventory specialist (2 expats).
 - **3.** Materials coordinator(1 expat and 1 local)
 - 4. Warehouse administrator 1 local and all the rest BOC assignees
- have good experience in Maximo in materials and warehouse management.
- Leading yearly inventory account by BOC and third party and make sure everything accurate and no mismatch between Maximo and actual stock.
- Providing the required training to warehouse staff and optimize their skills.
- Planning and arranging space for future projects and new wells.

- Execute multiple Management Information reports on weekly and bi-weekly frequency on outstanding MRs, PRs, materials with expired shelf life, stock duplication and working with inventory analyst to optimize our stock and have close to zero errors.
- Working with BLs and review their demands and make sure all the materials really required by business lines to prevent purchasing and unrequired materials.

Company: Shell Iraq petroleum development (Majnoon oilfield) SIPD

Period: JAN 2017- May 2018 (1 year and 5 months).

Position: - Procurement and Inventory analyst (inventory and materials management)-

In this role, I am supervising the procurement, inventory and stock checking requirements for shell Iraq Majnoon Materials department. My key responsibilities are as below.

- Responsible to Manage stocks of about 17000 unique materials, a stock value of about \$46millions and an additional valuated project stocks of \$6millions for wells and other project materials.
- Managing one subordinate (Stock checker), providing guidance and training as required, provide advice to new projects on inventory management.
- Proactively Contribute and share best practices and initiatives taken for improvements in global inventory management networks and initiatives.
- Agreeing the most cost-effective levels of stock aligned with the MM policy and matrix which is also aligned to the maintenance requirements, optimum stock levels will be established to support production requirements.
- Manage obsolescence of stock both in SAP and warehouse Inventory.
- Improve and optimize the materials supply chain by sharing facts and observations from the SAP systems and warehouse activities with the procurement team.
- Establish economic ordering quantities based on historical consumption/demand of materials.
- Execute multiple Management Information reports on weekly and bi-weekly frequency on outstanding PRs, Inventory situation and ZPMM (maintenance materials status).
- Execute and manage RFQs in SAP and get quotation from suppliers, evaluate quotes and execute PO award as per procurement policy.
- Manage PO Expediting based on the rush requirements
- Manage SAP MRP process, review and establish approved MRP levels and setting as per MM Policy.

From FEB 2014 – DEC 2016 (2 years 10 months)

Worked as a Warehouse supervisor (Inventory and Materials Management) – In this role I was responsible for Warehouse operation as per MM Policy of for Shell Iraq Majnoon. My key responsibilities were as below

- Administer warehousing activities in assigned areas in line with approved MM Policy and procedures.
- Administer and supervise the Goods receipt, storage and preservation process for Operating Spares/materials and improve and assure material availability to support plant operations and planned maintenance
- Implement working procedures for carrying out warehousing activities: materials receipt, handling & storage, warehouse & yard operations safety, Chemical handling, materials

preservation, and materials Issue to ensure all stored materials are fit for purpose when required and prevent loss of materials due to damage, theft, expiration, corrosion, or other means.

- Coordinate, maintain and implement HSE aspect of warehouse operations, safety plans and programs in line with company's HSE policies to ensure warehouse people are aware of safety requirements of all warehouse operations.
- Supervise the material receipt processes, (tallying, inspection, receipt in SAP system, binning, and correct documentation) and the material issuance process, Materials Return process, posting in SAP system and maintain a high service delivery level and system data accuracy and find alternative solutions to avoid disruption of production and maintenance operations due to delay in materials delivery.
- Achieve safety targets (as defined in Annual Goals)
- Maintain Professional standard of housekeeping in the Warehouses
- Lead several systematic material movements from current locations into future locations (including via temporary storage locations) as part of a major warehouse rehabilitation strategy
- Responsible for executing Storage and Preservation of Materials as per procedures
- Support MM Manager in Weekly and annual Stock audits.
- Support Warehouse team in Achieving 100% Inventory Accuracy in Warehouses- no mismatch between SAP inventory and physical inventory
- Coach and Train Warehouse team to build a good team and support succession planning and growth
- Assist the SOC team during their weekly audit visit to the warehouse by providing all necessary documentation and arranging physical identification for them so that they can complete their audit.

From JUN 2011 – JAN 2014 (2 years 7 months)

Worked for Schlumberger Company for drilling Fluids, in their Basra warehouse as a Warehouse Supervisor assistant (logistics Dept.) My key responsibilities were as below

- Administer and supervise the Goods receipt, storage and preservation process for Drilling Fluids
- Maintain Professional standard of housekeeping in the Warehouses
- Lead and manage the logistic process to deliver the Materials from One location into other Project locations. Arrange Transport and permit and deliver the goods to correct destination to support project operations
- Responsible for executing Storage and Preservation of Drilling Fluids and Chemicals as per approved procedures
- Coach and Train Warehouse team to build a good team and support succession planning and growth.

EDUCATION

Basra University/college of education -pure sciences, Basra, Iraq

Oct 2008 – May 2012

B. Sc.in computer science

IT SKILLS

- Windows & Office tools
- Microsoft office (word, excel, outlook, power point)
- SAP upstream blueprint (P16 Business process, P16-Iportal, PB7 business intelligence)
- SAP Business warehouse tools
- Maximo production materials managements

LANGUAGES

Arabic NativeEnglish Advanced